Ahmad M. Mustapha

Phone Number: +961 71 177 395

E-mail: ahmad.m.mustapha@hotmail.com

About Me

I am an AI engineer and Software Developer with diverse experience in academia and industry in multiple domains like Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, and Backend Development. I strive and enjoy positions that require creativity, problem-solving, and analytical skill sets.

Education

Education		
From 2018 to 2020	American University of Beirut (AUB) Master in Electric and Computer Engineering Major in Machine Intelligence Relevant Courses Taken: Applied Parallel Programming CUDA, Natural Language Processing, Adv. Data Science	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2015 to 2017	Lebanese University Master in Information systems and Data Intelligence Relevant Courses Taken: Data Mining, Big Data, Machine Learning, Decision Support, Distributed Applications, Real-Time Analysis Rank: 1/13	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2012 to 2015	Lebanese University Bachelor in Computer Science	Beirut, Lebanon
Experience		
From 2023 to Present	 Mustapha Technology Institute Founder and Lecturer Educational startup to fill educational gaps 	Beirut, Lebanon

Taught and developed learning materials

developers - Intro to Python - CV building

• E.g. Intro. to machine learning - Online presence for

From 2022 to 2023

Career Break Traveled

From 2021 to 2022

Java Developer Murex

Maintained a business module

- Agile Methodology
- Java, Python, Spring, Spring Boot, Open API, REST, ...

Beirut, Lebanon

2021 (8 months)	 Machine Learning Engineer Veer Managed a Machine Learning project from A to Z The project was related to Traffic Management Data Cleaning, Data Munging, Data Visualization Learning Prediction. Python, RNNs, LSTMs, Regression, Pandas, Numpy, Plotly, Dash. 	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2018 to 2020	 Research Assistance American University of Lebanon (AUB) Implementing/Improving Bleeding Edge Unsupervised Deep Learning Models Neural Networks Adversarial Samples Unsupervised Deep Learning Software Engineering Interaction with Machine Learning 	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2018 to 2020	 Multidisciplinary Engineer Self-Employed – Different Clients Computer vision models to detect vehicles in a tropical reserve in Africa. Computer vision models to detect illness through lung X-ray images Python Script to scrape and sort by price selected goods from different online providers Several Data Science and Machine Learning projects 	Beirut, Lebanon
Spring 2018-2019 Fall 2019-2020	 Teaching Assistance (277 hours total) American University of Lebanon (AUB) Teaching Introduction to Programming C++ / Matlab Teaching Computer Organization VHDL/PIC Software Tools (QT/Doxygen/Make Files/Unit Tests) 	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2017 to 2018	 Research Intern University of Versailles (UVSQ) Handling Multidimensional Data from Moving Air Pollution Sensors Use R libraries to transform data into functions Implement a Spark/Scala-based framework to read sensory values, interpolate them into functions, apply analysis on them, 	Versaille, France
From 2015 to 2016	 Occasional Private Tutor Introduction to programming (C/C++) Introduction to Web Development 	Beirut, Lebanon

Publications

- Mustapha A., Zeitouni K. and Taher Y. (2018). Towards Rich Sensor Data Representation Functional Data Analysis Framework for Opportunistic Mobile Monitoring. GISTAM
- Mustapha A., Khreich W., Masri W. (2021) A Deep Dive into Deep Cluster
- Mustapha A., Khreich W., Masri W. (2021) Inter-model Interpretability: Self-Supervised Models as a Case Study

Conferences

- 4th International Conference on Geographical Information Systems Theory, Applications and Management, GISTAM 2018, Funchal, Madeira, Portugal. Presented the paper Towards Rich Sensor Data Representation - Functional Data Analysis Framework for Opportunistic Mobile Monitoring.
- 34th IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering ICDE20 18. Paris. Guest.
- Junior Conference on Data Science and Engineering JDSE2018. Paris Saclay. Guest.

SKILLS

Languages: Fluent in English and Arabic.

Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork, Setting Goals, Planning

Technical Skills: Java, spring, Python, Scikit-Learn, R, Pytorch, Tensorflow, MatplotLib, Plotly, Dash

References

• Dr. Wes Masri, Professor at George Mason University, US, wmasri@gmu.edu

Portfolio

For more interesting details check my online portfolio or scan the QR code



Last Updated: October 23